I'm delighted to introduce this course
on Gemini CLI which is built with
Google's Jack Waters. Gemini CLI
especially with the release of the
Gemini 3 model has become one of my
favorite coding tools. It's created many
coding tasks including especially
front-end design and I find my usage of
it increasing. In this course you learn
how to use it both for coding and
perhaps less obviously some non-coding
tasks like organizing images and text on
your disc to help with writing tasks. I
also appreciate particularly that Gemini
CLI is open source. I know quite a few
people that have enjoyed looking at the
code, reading the prompts that Gemini
CLI uses, and really getting to
understand how it works.
Thanks for having me, Andrew. In this
course, you'll learn several useful
applications of Gemini CLI as an example
for software development, adding new
features to an existing website like a
conference session catalog, developing a
visual dashboard with data from local
files and a database, and automating
pull request reviews with Gemini CLI and
GitHub actions. But Gemini CLI is also
incredibly useful for complex use cases
beyond coding. You will learn how to
develop a full social media kit for an
event with Canva templates and nano
banana image generation and search
through all of your notes and slides
from your online courses like this one.
I use Aenti coding assistance all the
time for coding, but for non-coding
examples as well, I actually use an AI
assistant to organize my personal
workout plan by manipulating context
file within my own file system. And so
in this course you learn some best
practices for the non-coding tasks as
well. Because Frontier OM are so
powerful, they can carry out multiple
steps autonomously. Gemini CLI is an
interface that lets you access the raw
reasoning and function calling
capabilities of such a model. So after
giving the model access to tools like
disk access and GitHub and web search
and maybe some MCP service, you can then
instruct the model to perform a highle
task like coding an interactive game and
let it autonomously plan and execute a
complex workflow. You're totally right.
Agentic coding assistants shine when you
want to interact with a mix of local
tools installed on your computer as well
as cloud services like maybe Postman,
Figma, or Google Docs. This is where
using Gemini CLI in your terminal really
shines. In one use case in this course,
you'll source lead generation data from
your local machine and Google Sheets and
perform some analysis on it to create a
data dashboard. You'll learn all about
best practices and managing Gemini CLI
to complete these types of multi-tool
workflows. Everyone can be an AI builder
and I hope many people including
software developers but also people in
other job roles will be able to use
agentic assistance like Gemini CI to
carry out both coding and non-coding
tasks.
[Music]